FABIO A. NAVARRETE HIGUERA E-mail: fabioanh@gmail.com

General Information:



I'm a software engineer born in 1988 in Colombia. Good at problem solving and happy to always learn new things. In addition, I try to be creative using the different skills I possess. I like to keep diversified interests and enjoy programming. In fact, been doing it for over 15 years, 8 professional in different countries using a wide range of technologies. I've been also using Python and Kotlin in academic and personal projects. My strongest skills are related to the design and development of RESTful APIs. I'm eager to join a challenging environment where I can learn new tools and share my knowledge.

Academic Background:



Engineer (Bachelor Science) - Universidad Nacional de Colombia - 2010

Information Technology Tools:



Java 👙 Python 🤚 Linux Spring 🥏 Postgres 📭 Flutter Hibernate 🕻 Oracle 📿 TensorFlow RESTful {...} Jira 💠 Google Cloud Git 🊸 JMeter / Meter JUnit AWS aws Jenkins 🧌 Mockito

Solr Kotlin

Spring Boot

Miscellaneous:

Interested in the study of complex systems and Artificial Intelligence. Curious about social simulations and anthropology. Amateur drums player. I like to learn, teach, and improve my languages knowledge. Finally, I also like hiking and contemplation of nature.

Job History:



IPlytics(Sept 2020 - Present Germany) Intelectual property platform development for а start-up. Involved with Data-Pipelines and Web Application Spring Boot.



Proximus (Feb 2018 - Jun 2019 Belgium) Web-shop development involved API. with the Rest project with Scrum teams, around 30 people total.



Adneom (Jun 2016 - Dec 2017 Belgium) Consultancy work for support during migration of web application backend from Java to Python. BPost: JEE app.



Advaita (Nov 2013 - Sep 2015 USA) Development of a RESTful API using in order to further Spring, commercialise a stalled desktop product for a bioinformatics start-up.



Globant (Jun 2012 - Oct 2013 Colombia) JEE development. Worked on several applications for external clients. Additional tests automation tasks.



Intergrupo (Feb 2012 - May 2012 Colombia) Contractor for IBM. Development of a banking app using JEE.

Spoken Languages:

English - C1 level

French - B2 level German - A2 level

Italian - A2 evel

Spanish - Mother tongue